i.e. the tasks that take the input and generate a useful output,
即接收输入并生成有用输出的任务，
It is sometimes important for the model to reason in detail about a problem
有时模型在回答特定问题之
前需要详细推理问题，
And if you took our previous course: "ChartGPT Prompt Engineering for
如果你参加过我们之前的课程
“ChartGPT Prompt Engineering for
Developers", you will have seen a number of examples of this.
Developers”，你会看到
很多这方面的例子。
Sometimes a model might make reasoning errors by rushing to an incorrect
有时模型可能会因为急于得
出结论而出现推理错误，
conclusion, so we can reframe the query to request a series of relevant
所以我们可以重新构建查询，
要求模型进行一系列相关的
reasoning steps before the model provides a final answer, so that it can think
推理步骤在给出最终答案之前，这样它就
longer and more methodically about the problem.
可以更长时间、更有条理地思考问题。
And in general, we call this strategy of asking the model to reason about
总的来说，我们把让模型分步推理的策略
称为链式思维推理（Chain of Thought Reasoning）。
For some applications, the reasoning process that a model uses to arrive at
对于某些应用，模型在得出最终答案的过程中
所使用的推理过程可能不适合与用户共享。
on their own answers, but a model's reasoning process about the student's
自己解答问题，但模型对
学生解答的推理过程
solution could reveal the answer to the student.
可能会泄露答案给学生。
Inner monologue is a tactic that can be used to mitigate this.
“内心独白”是一种可以用来
缓解这个问题的策略。
And this is just a fancy way of saying, hiding the model's reasoning from the user.
这只是一种时髦的比喻，
意思是将模型的推理过程对用户进行隐藏。
The idea of inner monologue is to instruct the model to put parts of the output
内心独白的方案是指示模型
将输出的某些部分放入结构化格式，
that are meant to be hidden from the user into a structured format that makes passing them easy.
以便将这些内容隐藏起来不让用户看到。
Then, before presenting the output to the user, the output is passed and only part of the output is made visible.
然后，在将输出呈现给用户之前，
输出内容会被过滤，只有部分内容对用户可见。
So remember the classification problem from a previous video, where we asked
所以请记住前一个教学视
频中的分类问题，我们
the model to classify a customer query into a primary and secondary category.
要求模型将客户查询分类
为主要和次要类别。
And based on that classification, we might want to take different instructions.
根据这个分类，我们可能
想采取不同的指示。
Imagine the customer query had been classified into the product information category.
想象一下，客户查询已经被
归类到产品信息类别。
In the next instructions,
在接下来的指示中，
we'll want to include information about the products we have available.
我们会想要包含关于我们
拥有的产品的信息。
And so, in this case, the classification would have been: "Primary,
所以，在这种情况下，分类将是：
主类，一般查询，次类，产品信息。
And so let's dive into an example starting from there.
那么让我们从那里开始深入一个例子。
So let's start with our usual setup.
那么让我们从初始设置开始。
So for this inner monologue example,
对于这个内心独白的例子，
And now let's go through our system message.
现在让我们看一下系统消息。
And so what we're doing here is asking the model to reason about the answer before coming to its conclusion.
所以我们在这里所做的是
在得出结论之前要求模型对答案进行推理。
So the instruction is: "Follow these steps to answer the customer queries.
所以指令是：“按照这些
步骤回答客户查询。
The customer query will be delimited with four hashtags, our delimiter."
客户查询将用四个井号分
隔，我们的分隔符。”
So then we've split this up into steps.
然后我们把这个分成几步。
And a product category doesn't count.
并且产品类别不算数。
Step two, so if the user is asking about specific products,
第二步，因此，
如果用户询问有关特定产品的信息，
identify whether the products are in the following list.
确定这些产品是否在以下列表中。
And now we've included a list of available products.
现在我们已经包括了一份可用产品清单。
So here we have five available products that all varieties of laptops and these are all made up products.
所以这里我们有五种可用的产品，
它们都是各种类型的笔记本电脑，这些都是虚构的产品。
They were actually generated by GPT-4.
它们实际上是由GPT-4生成的。
In step three, if the message contains products in the list above,
在第三步中，如果消息包
含上述列表中的产品，
list any assumptions that the user is making in their message.
列出用户在其消息中所做的任何假设。
For example, that laptop X is bigger than laptop Y or
例如，笔记本电脑X比笔记本电脑Y大，或者
that laptop Z has a two year warranty, for example.
例如，笔记本电脑Z有两年保修期。
Step four is if the user made any assumptions,
第四步是，如果用户有任何假设，
figure out whether the assumption is true based on your product information.
根据您的产品信息判断假设是否正确。
And step five is: "First, politely correct the customer's incorrect assumptions if applicable."
第五步是：“首先，
礼貌地纠正客户的错误假设（如果适用）。”
Only mention or reference products in the list of five available products.
只提及或参考五个可用产品中的产品。
As these are the only five products that the store sells.
因为商店目前仅销售这五款产品。
And answer the customer in a friendly tone.
以友好的语气回答客户。
And these kind of very pedantic instructions are probably unnecessary for a more advanced language model like GPT-4.
对于像GPT-4这样更高级的语言模型
来说，这些非常繁琐的指示可能是不必要的。
And then we'll ask the model to use the following format.
然后我们将要求模型使用以下格式。
So step one, delimiter, it's reasoning.
所以第一步，分隔符，它的推理。
Step two, delimiter, reasoning, and so on.
第二步，分隔符，推理，依此类推。
Kind of cut off everything before.
把分隔符之前的所有内容都移除。
So our message is: "by how much is the BlueWave Chromebook more expensive than the TechPro Desktop?"
所以我们的消息是：
“BlueWave Chromebook比TechPro台式机贵多少？”
So let's take a look at these two products.
那么让我们看看这两款产品。
The BlueWave Chromebook is 249.99,
BlueWave Chromebook售价为249.99美元，
and the TechPro Desktop is actually 999.99.
而TechPro台式机实际上
售价为999.99美元。
This is not actually true.
这实际上并不正确。
And so let's see how the model handles this user request.
那么让我们看看模型如何
处理这个用户请求。
So we'll format into our messages array, and we'll get our response.
所以我们将其格式化为
我们的消息数组，然后我们会得到返回结果。
And then we'll print it.
然后我们会打印出来。
And so what we're hoping for
所以我们希望的是
is that the model takes all of these different steps and realizes that
模型能够理解所有这些
不同的步骤，并意识到
then follows the final step to politely correct the user.
在最后一步礼貌地纠正用户。
And so within this one prompt, we've actually maintained
所以在这一个提示（Prompt）中，
我们实际上保持了
a number of different complex states that the system could be in.
系统可能处于的许多不同的复杂状态。
So at any given point, there could be a different output from the previous step,
所以在任何给定的时刻，
都可能有来自前一步的不同输出，
and we would want to do something different.
我们会想要做一些不同的事情。
For example, if the user hadn't made any assumptions in step three,
例如，如果用户在第三步没有做任何假设，
then in step four, we wouldn't actually have any output.
那么在第四步，
我们实际上不会有任何输出。
So this is a pretty complicated instruction for the model.
所以这对模型来说是一
个相当复杂的指令。
So let's see if it did it right.
那么让我们看看它是否做对了。
So step one, the user is asking a question about specific products.
所以第一步，用户在询问
关于特定产品的问题。
They're asking about the price difference between these two products.
他们在询问这两款产品之间的价格差异。
The user assumes that the BlueWave Chromebook is more expensive than
用户认为BlueWave Chromebook比
the TechBook Pro, and this assumption is actually incorrect.
TechBook Pro更贵，
而这个假设实际上是错误的。
It's reasoning through, taking longer to think about the problem.
它通过推理，花更长的时
间来思考这个问题。
In the same way that a human would also take some time to reason about
就像人类在回答任何问题时
也需要花一些时间来推理一样，
an answer to any given question, the model performs better if it also has time to think.
如果模型也有时间去思
考，它的表现会更好。
And so the final response to the user is the BlueWave Chromebook is actually less expensive than the TechBook Pro.
所以最后对用户的回答是
BlueWave Chromebook实际上比TechBook Pro便宜。
The TechBook Pro desktop costs $999.99, while the BlueWave Chromebook costs $249.99.
TechBook Pro台式电脑售价为999.99美元，
而BlueWave Chromebook售价为249.99美元。
And so let's see another example of a user message.
让我们看另一个用户消息的例子。
And also at this point, feel free to pause the video and try your own messages.
此时，也可以随时暂停视频，
尝试您自己的消息。
So let's format this user message.
让我们格式化这个用户消息。
So the question is: "Do you sell TVs?"
所以问题是：“你们卖电视吗？”
And if you remember in our product list, we've only listed different computers.
如果您还记得我们的产品列表中，
我们只列出了不同的电脑。
So let's see what the model says.
让我们看看模型会说什么。
So in this case, step one, the user is asking if the store sells TVs, but
所以在这种情况下，第一步，
用户询问商店是否出售电视，但是
TVs are not listed in the available products.
电视并未列在可用产品中。
So as you can see, the model then skips to the response to user step because it
因此，如您所见，模型
接着跳到回应用户的步骤，因为它
realizes that the intermediary steps are not actually necessary.
意识到中间步骤实际上并不需要。
I will say that we did ask for the output in this specific format.
我要说的是，我们确实要求
以这种特定格式输出。
And so in this case, our response to the user is, I'm sorry, but
在这种情况下，
我们对用户的回复是：“对不起，但是
And then it lists the available products.
然后列出了可用的产品。
So what we can do is actually just cut the string at the last occurrence
所以我们可以做的
实际上就是在最后一次出现
of this delimiter token or string of four hashtags.
这个分隔符标记
或四个井号字符串的地方分割字符串。
And then only print the final part of the model output.
然后只打印模型输出的最后一部分。
So let's write some code to get only the final part of this string.
让我们编写代码来获取这个
字符串的最后一部分。
So we're going to use a try except block to gracefully handle errors in case
因此，我们将使用一个
try except 块来优雅地处理错误，以防
the model has some kind of unpredictable output and
模型有某种不可预测的输出，而且
doesn't actually use these characters.
实际上并不使用这些字符。
And then we're gonna split the string at the delimiter string.
然后我们要使用分隔符来
将字符串分割成数组。
we just want to get the last item in the output list.
然后只想要输出数组中的最后一项。
And then we're going to strip any white space.
最后再去除前后空格。
Because as you can see, there might be white space after the characters.
因为如您所见，字符后面可能会有空格。
Then we're going to catch any errors.
然后我们要处理任何可能得异常错误。
And have a fallback response.
并有一个备用返回结果。
Which is, sorry.
那就是：
“对不起，我现在遇到了麻烦。
Please try asking another question.
请尝试提问另一个问题。”
And then let's print our final response.
然后让我们打印最终结果。
And so as you can see, we just cut the string to get this final output.
如您所见，我们只是
对字符串裁剪，从而获得最终输出。
And so this is what we would show to the user if we were building this into an application.
如果我们将它集成到应用程序中，
这就是我们要向用户展示的内容。
And overall, I just want to call out,
总的来说，我只是想指出，
this prompt might be slightly convoluted for this task.
这个提示（Prompt）
对于这个任务可能有些复杂。
You might not actually need all of these intermediate steps.
你实际上可能不需要所有这些中间步骤。
And so why don't you try and see if you can find an easier way to do the same task in your own prompt.
所以，为什么不尝试看看
你能否在你自己的提示（Prompt）中
找到一种更简单的方法来完成相同的任务。
So definitely good to try a number of different prompts before deciding to use one.
所以在决定使用一个
提示（Prompt）之前，最好尝试
多种不同的提示（Prompt）。
by splitting these complex tasks into a series of simpler subtasks,
通过将这些复杂任务分解成
一系列更简单的子任务，